<?xml version="1.0"?>
<detail><item><name>周一帆 副教授</name><wait1>职称副教授办公室523联系电话025-52090529E-mailyifan.zhou@seu.edu.cn</wait1><wait4_kecheng>教授课程应用统计学可靠性工程机器人工程程序设计及算法语言II计算机综合课程设计创造学与创造力开发训练</wait4_kecheng><wait_yanjiu>研究方向1.可靠性与设备维修策略优化2.统计质量控制3.制造业企业信息化</wait_yanjiu><wait_huojiang>论文著作Journal papers:[1]Zhou,Y., T. Lin, et al. (2016)”Maintenance Optimisation of a Parallel-series System with Stochastic and Economic Dependence under Limited Maintenance Capacity.”Reliability Engineering&amp; System Safety. 155: 137–146. (SCI)[2]Zhou, Y., T. Lin, et al. (2015)”An Effective Approach to Reducing Strategy Space for Maintenance Optimisation of Multistate Series-parallel Systems.”Reliability Engineering &amp; System Safety. 135: 40–53. (SCI)[3]Zhou, Y., Z. Zhang (2015)”Optimal Maintenance of a Series Production System with Two Multi-component Subsystems and an Intermediate Buffer.”Maintenance and Reliability. 17 (2): 314–325. (SCI)[4]Zhou, Y., Z. Zhang, et al. (2013) “Maintenance Optimisation of a Multi-state Series-parallel System Considering Economic Dependence and State-dependent Inspection Intervals.” Reliability Engineering &amp; System Safety. 111: 248–259. (SCI)[5]Zhou, Y., Yong. Sun, et al. (2011) “Latent Degradation Indicators Estimation and Prediction: a Monte Carlo Approach.”Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing 25(1): 222-236. (SCI)[6]Zhou, Y., L. Ma, et al. (2011) “Maintenance Strategy Optimization Using a Continuous-state Partially Observable Semi-Markov Decision Process.”Microelectronics Reliability 51(2): 300-309. (SCI)[7] Zhou, Y., L. Ma, et al. (2009). “Asset Life Prediction Using Multiple Degradation Indicators and Failure Events: A Continuous State Space Model Approach.”Maintenance and Reliability 11(4): 72-81. (SCI)[8]Zhang, Z.,Y. Zhou, et al. (2012). “Condition-based Maintenance Optimisation without a Predetermined Strategy Structure for a Two-component Series System.”Maintenance and Reliability14(2): 120-129. (SCI)[9]Gan, S., Z. Zhang,Y. Zhou, J. Shi. “Joint optimization of maintenance, buffer, and spare parts for a production system.”Applied Mathematical Modelling, In Press. (SCI)[10]Gan, S., Z. Zhang,Y. Zhou, J. Shi. (2013) “Intermediate Buffer Analysis for a Production System.”Applied Mathematical Modelling, 37, 8785–8795. (SCI)[11]Zhang, Z., W. Gao,Y. Zhou and et al.（2012）. “Reliability Modeling and Maintenance Optimization of the Diesel System in Locomotives.”Maintenance and Reliability. 14(4):302-311. (SCI)Conference papers:[1] Zhou, Y., Z. Zhang, et al. (2013). “An Efficient maintenance Optimisation Method for Series-parallel Systems Using Stochastic Ordering and Revenue Difference Boundaries”. ICQR2MSE 2013, IEEE (EI)[2] Zhou, Y., Z. Zhang, et al. (2012). “Maintenance Optimisation of a Series-parallel System with Multi-state Components Considering Economic Dependence”. ICQR2MSE 2012, IEEE (EI)[3] Zhou, Y., L. Ma, et al. (2010). “Maintenance decision-making using a continuous-state partially observable semi-Markov decision process”. PHM2010, IEEE (EI) (recommend as “best paper” by the IEEE-PHM conference)[4] Zhou, Y., L. Ma, et al. (2009). “Asset Life Prediction Using Multiple Degradation Indicators and Lifetime Data: a Gamma-Based State Space Model Approach”. ICRMS 2009, IEEE (EI) (recommend as “best paper” by the ICRMS conference)</wait_huojiang><wait2_xuexi>学习经历1999年9月-2003年7月东南大学机械工程学院学士2003年8月-2006年10月东南大学机械工业学院硕博连读2006年10月-2010年4月澳大利亚昆士兰科技大学环境与工程学院博士</wait2_xuexi><wait3_gongzuo>工作经历2010年5月至今东南大学机械工程学院讲师/副教授</wait3_gongzuo></item></detail>
