<?xml version="1.0"?>
<detail><item><name>章寅</name><wait1>职称           讲师办公室         机械楼436联系电话       15077867755E-mail        yin.zhang@seu.edu.cn      </wait1><wait4_kecheng>研究方向1. 微纳米流体器件设计与制造2. 纳米流体输运特性3. 纳米材料热学及机械性能</wait4_kecheng><wait_yanjiu>论文著作1. ZHANG Y,WU G, SI W, et al. Ionic current modulation from DNA translocation throughnanopores under high ionic strength and concentration gradients [J]. Nanoscale,2017, 9(2): 930-9. (SCI, IF=7.76)2. ZHANG Y,LIU L, SHA J J, et al. Nanopore detection of DNA molecules in magnesiumchloride solutions [J]. Nanoscale Res Lett, 2013, 8:245. (SCI, IF=2.584)3. ZHANG Y,WU G, SI W, et al. Retarding and manipulating of DNA molecules translocationthrough nanopores [J]. Chinese Sci Bull, 2014, 59(35): 4908-17. (SCI, IF=1.789)4. ZHANG Y, WU G, MA J, et al. Temperature effecton translocation speed and capture rate of nanopore-based DNA detection [J].Sci China Technol Sci, 2015, 58(3): 519-25. (SCI, IF=1.441)5. ZHANG Y, LIU L, SHA J, et al. Fabricationof Al2O3 Nanopore Sensors for DNA Detection;proceedings of the ASME 2013 International Mechanical Engineering Congress andExposition, F, 2013 [C]. American Society of Mechanical Engineers. (EI)6. ZHANG Y, WU G S, SI W, et al. Nanopore PositivePulse Detection of DNA with Salt Gradients [J]. Key Engineering Materials, 2015,656-657: 567-72. (EI)7. WUG, ZHANG Y, SI W, et al. Integrated solid-state nanopore devicesfor third generation DNA sequencing [J]. Sci China Technol Sci, 2014,57(10): 1925-35. (SCI, IF=1.441)8. SIW, ZHANG Y, WU G S, et al.DNA sequencing technology based on nanopore sensors by theoretical calculationsand simulations [J]. Chinese Sci Bull, 2014, 59(35): 4929-41. (SCI, IF=1.789)9. SHA J J, SHI H J, ZHANGY, et al. Salt Gradient Improving Signal-to-Noise Ratio in Solid-StateNanopore [J]. Acs Sensors, 2017, 2(4): 506-12. (SCI)10. YANGL, HONG T, ZHANG Y, et al. Amicrofluidic diode for sorting and immobilization of Caenorhabditis elegans[J]. Biomed Microdevices, 2017, 19(2): 38. (SCI, IF=2.227)11. MAJ, ZHANG Q, ZHANG Y, et al. Arapid and simple method to draw polyethylene nanofibers with enhanced thermalconductivity [J]. Appl Phys Lett, 2016, 109(3): 033101. (SCI, IF=3.142)12. YANGL, YANG Y, ZHANG Q, ZHANG Y,et al. Thermal conductivity of individual silicon nanoribbons [J]. Nanoscale,2016, 8(41): 17895-901. (SCI, IF=7.76)13. YANGJ, TANG H, ZHAO Y, ZHANG Y, etal. Thermal conductivity of zinc blende and wurtzite CdSenanostructures [J]. Nanoscale, 2015, 7(38): 16071-8. (SCI, IF=7.76)14. TANGH, WANG X, XIONG Y, ZHAO Y, ZHANG Y,et al. Thermoelectric characterization of individual bismuth selenidetopological insulator nanoribbons [J]. Nanoscale, 2015, 7(15): 6683-90. (SCI, IF=7.76)</wait_yanjiu><wait_huojiang>发明专利1. 陈云飞，章寅，刘磊，沙菁㛃，袁志山，倪中华，易红. 一种用于DNA检测的多电极纳米孔装置及其制造方法. 发明专利：201310054855.8，2013. (授权)2. 陈云飞，司伟，伍根生，章寅，沙菁㛃，刘磊. 一种多通道阵列式DNA测序系统及其测序方法. 发明专利：201410320550.1，2014. (授权)</wait_huojiang><wait2_xuexi>学习经历2011.08-2017.06 东南大学，机械设计及理论，研究生/博士2014.11-2016.12 美国范德堡大学，机械工程，CSC联合培养博士研究生2008.09-2011.07 兰州理工大学，控制理论与控制工程，研究生/硕士2004.09-2008.07 河海大学，电子信息工程，本科/学士</wait2_xuexi><wait3_gongzuo>工作经历2017.06月-至今，东南大学，机械工程学院，讲师</wait3_gongzuo></item></detail>
