<?xml version="1.0"?>
<detail><item><name>丁晓蔚</name><jobTitle>职称:  副教授</jobTitle><position>职位:  </position><department>系别:  信息管理科学系</department><office>办公室:  0</office><email>邮箱:  dingxiaowei@nju.edu.cn</email><officePhone>办公电话:  </officePhone><cellphoneNumber>手机号码:  </cellphoneNumber><researchAreas>&#13;
              &#13;
                      丁晓蔚博士毕业于美国斯坦福大学先进金融科技实验室，获金融工程学博士和统计学博士（辅），有华尔街著名金融机构实战经验。其研究试图将区块链、人工智能、大数据等信息技术驱动的金融经济研究与社会文化研究结合起来，从底层架构和上层应用两个层面打通，进行学科交叉融合研究。基于大数据、人工智能和区块链，从金融经济的角度研究社会文化，从社会文化的角度研究金融经济，或许能获得一些新见。丁晓蔚博士拥有十余年将区块链、人工智能、大数据应用于金融科技和金融工程的经验，长期致力于该方向的理论积累和实战探索。其攻读博士学位期间的研究方向为：金融（大）数据的统计分析和金融衍生品的随机建模。有效探索了基于时变生成过程的信用衍生品模型和定价、对冲和风险管理的理论和方法。随导师（斯坦福大学先进金融科技实验室主任）在国际信用衍生品及其风险管理的理论研究方面做了一些原创性工作。在UT Dallas Top 24商学院期刊等国际顶尖期刊发表论文数篇，所发论文总计被引约300次（迄今为止，其中一篇论文在当年同期刊所有论文中总引用数排名第一，在近10年同期刊所有论文中总引用数排名前2.4%）。部分研究成果被微软及华尔街著名投行采用或借鉴。也曾师从美国金融学会前主席达菲教授（斯坦福商学院教授），得到其高度评价，因此受邀任其助教助研，达菲教授并向摩根斯坦利和高盛等知名金融机构进行推荐。丁晓蔚博士曾先后在美国摩根大通（实习）、摩根斯坦利、世界顶尖金融名企城堡对冲基金公司（连续多年位列世界前10名，数年名列世界第1；被Financial Times评为人类历史上最赚钱对冲基金第5名；为首批经批准进入中国的6家国际顶级对冲基金之一）等金融机构工作。其参与的多个项目，核心是如何在海量金融（大）数据中，进行数据挖掘、机器学习和统计建模，在归纳出规律的基础上，对市场的变动和风险进行预测，采用高性能并行计算等金融高科技技术，在瞬息万变的市场中实时或非实时捕捉盈利机会，采用基于量化的方法做出投资决策，并管控风险。工作内容：大数据、人工智能、金融衍生品、资产证券化、结构化金融、风险管理、量化投资、统计建模、金融高性能体系架构及分布式软件系统平台设计和研究等。曾主持或参与多个金融科技、区块链金融、互联网金融、大数据金融、数据挖掘、人工智能金融、人工智能医疗等项目。曾领导数十IT的软件团队从零到有打造高性能金融大数据分析平台、高速交易平台、大数据人工智能量化投资决策系统、高性能风险管理平台、区块链衍生品智能交易平台等。在金融科技方面拥有专利。在金融科技（含金融工程、金融信息、金融统计、金融数学、金融经济）、社会文化和区块链人工智能大数据应用这几个方面，其研究团队都有一定基础和“板凳深度”。在这几个方面结合的研究领域（区块链金融创新、人工智能金融创新、大数据金融创新）中，团队正朝着国际前沿目标进行积累和发力。区块链、人工智能、大数据时代，传统学科界限正在急速消亡，课题组长期致力于文理科打通的学科交叉跨界融合研究。在欢迎计算机、软件、数学、统计、物理等背景的理工科同学报名加盟之外，也欢迎新闻出版、金融经济、法律商学、社会公管等人文社科方向的同学加盟。并不需要掌握技术和金融知识，只需要对上述方向的跨界融合研究有相当的兴趣并愿意学习即可。团队成员来自于不同背景、各具优势、兼容并蓄、交叉碰撞、教学相长。也可以跨专业指导外院系各级学生。课题组特色：        - 人工智能、区块链、大数据信息技术与金融经济、人文社会的深度融合       - 人工智能、区块链、大数据的深度融合       - 人文社科与数理工科的深度融合       - 理论与实战（行业前沿）的深度融合       - 学业发展与职业发展（名校名企、创新创业等）的深度融合       - 国际前沿与本土实践的深度融合       - 视野眼界与实干落地的深度融合课题组学生成绩：       - 2018美国大学生数学建模竞赛特等奖 Outstanding Winner, Top 0.11%.       - 哈佛大学交换       - 大二撰写国际SCI论文       - C刊论文多次被“三大”（《新华文摘》、《中国社会科学文摘》、《人大报刊复印资料》）转载转引       - 花旗杯等金融相关软件大赛二等奖等       - 毕业生去向：国内清华等名校名企，国外哥伦比亚大学、宾夕法尼亚大学、加州大学洛杉矶分校等课题组开课：       - 《区块链+人工智能与金融创新》（校级双创平台课，校级“千层次”课程），教授区块链编程、人工智能编程，强调实践应用，强调技术+金融的深度融合，培养真正既懂技术又懂金融的人才，强调国际前沿和行业前沿。既培养（金融）软件工程师，又培养（金融）数据工程师、科学家。课堂内容为【推公式（数学统计建模），码代码（编程开发、数据挖掘），金融经济】三元组。教师本人热爱推公式（多次数学竞赛获奖）、码代码（多次信息学竞赛、软件大赛获奖），也同样热爱金融经济，有华尔街实战经验。       - 《大数据出版文化（科技）》（院级C类课程），内容为区块链、人工智能、大数据驱动的出版文化科技。  Research in Advanced Interdisciplinary Sciences:Analytics &amp; Learning for Financial, Social and Human Dynamics(ALFSHD) LaboratoryBlockchain, Artificial Intelligence, Big Data &amp; FinTech(BAIBFT) LaboratoryAt Stanford University(the now-named Advanced Financial Technologies Laboratory), Xiaowei mainly worked on statistical analysis of financial data and stochastic modeling of financial derivatives. He spent a few years building models for capturing correlated default risks and developing pricing, hedging and risk management frameworks for Credit Derivatives.  After graduation from Stanford University, Xiaowei devoted himself to the field of Quantitative Finance, Quantitative Trading and Quantitative Wealth Management in the hedge funds industry on Wall Street. He worked as a quantitative trader/strategist at Morgan Stanley and Citadel Investment Group(one of the world's leading quantitative hedge funds). Leveraging on ultra-high speed computing and trading capabilities, his team:-built high performance distributed computer systems to monitor the global financial markets in real time;-built algorithmic, stochastic and statistical models to mine the financial and economic big data, characterize the dynamics of market movements, forecast the market evolution, capture the statistical arbitrage opportunities and make rapid trading and risk management decisions confronting the turbulent financial markets. Xiaowei had also worked as Chief Quantitative Investment Officer at the Department of Asset Management of GuoTaiJunAn (one of the top Chinese investment banks) Futures Ltd. Hedge Funds industry is known for "more money than God". Yet money isn't everything. Having worked on numerous data mining and model-building projects, in the pursuit for the “perfect models”, Xiaowei began to question himself: why do models work, when will models fail and what are the boundaries between human and machine. He gradually gained interests in the study of human-being, human emotion, human society and human culture especially the Chinese culture. Ultimately, he is interested in human minds. Driven by the desire to understand the structural and co-evolutionary dynamics and interactions of human and machines better, he returned to academia and back home to Nanjing University. Driven by Big Data and AI(the main thread and theme), his main research topics are:-Data Analytics &amp; Learning for Humanities and Social Science:    -Machine Learning in Humanities and Social Science;    -Digital Publishing, Reading and Culture Evolution;    -Media, Social Networks and Knowledge Engineering;    -Risk Society and Risk Management;    -Digital Cultural Creative Industry(Publishing, Movie, Animation, etc);    -Machine Learning in Health/Life Sciences.-Data Analytics &amp; Learning for Finance:    -Machine Learning(Reinforcement Learning, Recurrent Neural Networks, Deep Learning etc. ) in Finance;    -Derivative Pricing;    -Quantitative Trading, Investing and Wealth Management;    -Risk Management;    -Market Microstructure;    -Consumer Credits;    -FinTech, Blockchain, Internet Finance and Sharing Economy;     -Digital Currency;    -Blockchain + AI Securitization/Structured Finance;    -Hedge Funds, Private Equity Funds, etc.Xiaowei loves both mathematical and statistical reasoning, programming(he had won a few Information Olympiads or programming competitions), literature writing and philosophical thinking. He publishes research articles on both Chinese and English journals. He collaborates with culture/media researchers, psychologists, sociologists, computer scientists, mathematicians, physicists, statisticians and financial economists at leading academic institutions and industry organizations all around the globe. If you are interested in joining or collaborating with his research group, please feel free to drop him a line at dingxiaowei@nju.edu.cn. Students and collaborators from all backgrounds including humanities, social, law and medical sciences are welcome.&#13;
              &#13;
                &#13;
            </researchAreas><researchProject>&#13;
              &#13;
                 Drawing upon his financial industry expertise and experience, Xiaowei had participated and led various industry-level projects in high performance distributed trading systems and large scale financial big data mining platforms, algorithms and models. Some of his projects involved analyzing global financial markets and mining billions of accounts in real-time or near real-time. He emphasizes both mathematical/statistical theory and real-world applications. A sampler of his new projects after returning to the academia and Nanjing University:    -Reinforcement Learning in Financial Trading;    -Deep Learning in Finance;    -Recurrent Neural Networks and Stochastic Processes for Financial Time Series Forecasting;    -Intelligent Robots in FinTech and Law;    -Digital Currency；    -Blockchain + AI Securitization/Structured Finance；    -Time Series Analysis for Reading and Chinese Cultural Risk Management;    -Social Networks and Media Risk Engineering - Characterization, Forecasting and Decision Making;    -Pricing and Risk Management for Intellectual Property;    -Intelligent Creative Industries;    -Investing and Financing in Chinese Creative Industries;    -Analytics &amp; Learning for Health/Life Sciences. Please feel free to drop Xiaowei a line to share your interesting ideas. He is particularly interested in cool interdisciplinary ideas that explore the deep side of human nature and/or the boundaries of human/machine.&#13;
              &#13;
                &#13;
            </researchProject><book>&#13;
              &#13;
                Selected Representative Publications(Google Scholar Citation #: 297):    -A Display Simulation Toolbox for Image Quality Evaluation, Joyce Farrell, Gregory Ng, Xiaowei Ding, Kevin Larson and Brian Wandell, Journal of Display Technology, 4(2):262-270, 2008.    -Time-Changed Birth Processes and Multi-Name Credit Derivatives, Xiaowei Ding, Kay Giesecke and Pascal Tomecek, Operations Research(UT Dallas Top 24 Journals), 57(4), 990-1005, 2009.    -A Top-Down Approach to Multi-Name Credit, Kay Giesecke, Lisa Goldberg and Xiaowei Ding, Operations Research(UT Dallas Top 24 Journals), 59(2), 283-300, 2011.    -A Novel Bitstream Level Joint Channel Error Concealment Scheme for Realtime Video over Wireless Networks, Xiaowei Ding and Kaushik Roy, IEEE INFOCOM, 2004. Selected Working Papers &amp; Technical Reports:    -Statistical Arbitrage in High Frequency Trading Based on Limit Order Book Dynamics, Murat Ahmed, Anwei Chai, Xiaowei Ding, Yunjiang Jiang, Yunting Sun, 2009.    -Automatic Trading and Statistical Arbitrage – A System Integration Approach, 2009.    -Forecasting Loan Performance Using Big Data, 2015.   - Stock-RCNN: Stock Movement Learning by Opportunity Window Detection, 2017.   - A Blockchain-Based Intelligent Trading System for Securitization and Structured Finance, 2018. &#13;
              &#13;
                &#13;
            </book></item></detail>
