<?xml version="1.0"?>
<detail><item><name>李江</name><jobTitle>职称:  教授</jobTitle><position>职位:  </position><department>系别:  信息管理科学系</department><office>办公室:  A221</office><email>邮箱:  lijiang@nju.edu.cn</email><officePhone>办公电话:  </officePhone><cellphoneNumber>手机号码:  </cellphoneNumber><researchAreas>&#13;
              &#13;
               1. 科学数据，例如，ORCID数据集中科学家流动、海归归海，微软学术数据集中的国际合作，Publons数据集中的同行评议贡献与科学产出的关系等；2. 科学学与科学计量，例如，科学家成长过程中的影响因素，科学中的『睡美人』现象和『昙花一现』现象，学科交叉与创新的关系等。欢迎对以上方向感兴趣的同学报考博士！&#13;
              &#13;
                &#13;
            </researchAreas><researchProject>&#13;
              &#13;
                 1. 李江 主编，《科学家修炼指南》，科学出版社，20182. 孙建军、李江，《网络信息计量理论、工具与应用》，科学出版社，2010&#13;
              &#13;
                &#13;
            </researchProject><book>&#13;
              &#13;
                SSCI收录（*代表通讯作者）1. Min, C., Ding, Y., Li, J., et al. (2018). Innovation or imitation: The diffusion of citations. Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology (JASIST), https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/asi.24047.2. Liu, M., Hu, X., &amp; Li, J. (*) (2018). Knowledge flow in china’s humanities and social sciences. Quality &amp; Quantity, 52(2), 607-626.3. Liu, M., Shi, D., &amp; Li, J. (*) (2017). Double-edged sword of interdisciplinary knowledge flow from hard sciences to humanities and social sciences: evidence from china. Plos One, 12(9), e0184977.4. Shi, D., Rousseau, R., Yang, L., Li, J. (*) (2017). A journal’s impact factor is influenced by changes in publication delays of citing journals. Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology (JASIST), 68(3), 780-789.5. Li, J. (*), &amp; Shi, D. (2016). Sleeping beauties in genius work: when were they awakened? Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology, 67(2), 432–440.6. Sun, J., Min, C., &amp; Li, J. (*) (2016). A vector for measuring obsolescence of scientific articles. Scientometrics, 107(2), 745-757.7. Li, J. (*), &amp; Ye, F. Y. (2016). Distinguishing sleeping beauties in science. Scientometrics, 108(2), 821-828.8. Li, J. (*), &amp; Li, Y. (2015). Patterns and evolution of coauthorship in China’s humanities and social sciences. Scientometrics, 102(3), 1997-2010.9. Huang, C., Su, J., Xie, X., Ye, X., Li, Z., Porter, A., Li, J. (*). (2015). A bibliometric study of China’s science and technology policies: 1949-2010. Scientometrics, 102(2), 1521-1539.10. Li, J. (*), Qiao, L., Li, W., Jin, Y. (2015). Rejoinder to “Chinese-language articles are biased in citations”. Journal of Informetrics, 9(3), 591.11. Li, J. (*), Qiao, L., Li, W., Jin, Y. (2014). Chinese-language articles are not biased in citations: Evidences from Chinese-English bilingual journals in Scopus and Web of Science. Journal of Informetrics, 8(4), 912-916.12. Li, J., Shi, D., Zhao, S. X., Ye, F. Y. (2014). A study of the “heartbeat spectra”for “sleeping beauties”. Journal of Informetrics, 8(3), 493-502.13. Li, J. (*). (2014). Citation curves of “all-elements-sleeping-beauties”: “flash in the pan”first and then “delayed recognition”. Scientometrics, 100(2), 595-601.14. Huang, C., Su, J., Xie, X., Li, J. (*). (2014). Basic research is overshadowed by applied research in China: a policy perspective. Scientometrics, 99(3), 501-507.15. Li, J. &amp; Ye, Y. (2014). A Probe into the Citation Patterns of High-quality and High-impact Publications. Malaysian Journal of Library and Information Science, 19(2), 31-47.16. Zhao, X., Zhang, L., Li, J., et al. (2014). Abstracting the Core Subnet of Weighted Networks Based on Link Strengths. Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology, 65(5), 984-994.17. Li, J. &amp; Ye, Y. (2012). The phenomenon of all-elements-sleeping-beauties in scientific literature. Scientometrics, 92(3), 795-799.18. Li, J., Sanderson, M., Willett, P., Norris, M., &amp; Oppenheim, C. (2010). Ranking of Library and Information Science Researchers: Comparison of Data Sources for Correlating Citation Data and Expert Judgments. Journal of Informetrics, 4(4), 554-563.19. Li, J. &amp; Willett, P. (2010). Bibliometric analysis of Chinese research in Cyclisation, Maldi-Tof and Antibiotics. Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling, 50(1), 22-29.20. Li, J. &amp; Willett, P. (2009). ArticleRank: A PageRank-based alternative to numbers of citations for analyzing citation networks. Aslib Proceedings, 61(6), 605-618.21. Qiu, J., Li, Y., Li, J. &amp; Ren, Q. (2008). An exploratory study on Substantive Co-link Analysis: A modification to Total Co-link Analysis. Scientometrics, 76(2), 327-341.SCI收录1. Zhao, S. X., Li, J.(*). (2015). Citation peaks in modern science: 1900–2010. Current Science, 109(9), 1523-1525.2. Li, J. (*). (2013). Shrinkage of Chinese Internet resources. Current Science, 104(10), 1271-1273.3. Li, J. (*). (2013). Uncited SSCI publications in China. Current Science, 104(11), 1642-1643.国际会议论文（Web of Science收录）1. Huang, C., Yue, X., Chen, J., Xu, W., Li, J.(*) The effect of “open access”on journal impact factors: A causal analysis of medical journals. Wuhan: 16thISSI, 2017. 10. 16-20.2. Sun, J., Min, C., Li, J.(*). A vector for measuring obsolescence of scientific articles. Istanbul: 15thISSI, 2015.6.28-7.3. CSSCI收录（部分）1. 李江, 李东, 冯培桦,等. 基于专长吻合度、学术影响力与社会关联值的专家推荐模型研究. 情报学报, 2017, 36(4):338-345.2. 李江, 姜明利, 李玥婷. 引文曲线的分析框架研究——以诺贝尔奖得主的引文曲线为例. 中国图书馆学报, 2014, 40(2):41-49.3. 黄萃,任弢,李江,赵培强,苏竣. 责任与利益：基于政策文献量化分析的中国科技创新政策府际合作关系演进研究. 管理世界,2015, (12): 74-87.4. 李江, 刘源浩, 黄萃, 苏竣. 用文献计量研究重塑政策文本数据分析——政策文献计量的起源、迁移与方法创新. 公共管理学报, 2015, 12(2): 138-144.5. 李江. 科学中的“睡美人”与“昙花一现”现象评述[J]. 大学图书馆学报, 2016, 34(3):38-43.6. 李江, 李东, 俞欣辰. 文献计量学研究共同体的特征与变迁:1994—2014年. 图书情报知识, 2016, (3):71-79.7. 李江. 跨学科性的概念框架与测度. 图书情报知识, 2014, (3): 87-93.8. 李江. 基于引文的知识扩散研究评述. 情报资料工作, 2013, (4): 36-40.&#13;
              &#13;
                &#13;
            </book></item></detail>
